Mike Vanbuskirk

DevOps Engineer I Grand Rapids, MI I linkedin.com/in/mikevanbuskirk

education

2009 - 2012 WGU BSc - Networks Design & Management

programming

Python, Bash, Golang, Node.js

technologies

AWS, Git, Docker, Terraform, Chef, Puppet, Ansible, Consul, Nomad, Vagrant, Packer, TravisCl, Jenkins, New Relic, DataDog, Heroku

summary

Lead engineer specializing in DevOps, cloud-first architecture, and automation. I'm also a blogger and freelance technical content creator. Experience supporting some of the largest CDN, Cloud, and E-Commerce platforms in the world. I enjoy designing complex systems that employ modern DevOps methodologies, and like to emphasize microservices and serverless architecture wherever possible. I'm passionate about technology, like solving difficult problems, and never pass up an opportunity to expand my skillset.

experience

May 2020 - Present I IOD

Freelance Technical Writer

Freelance technical content creation, focusing on DevOps, Cloud, and Serverless technology.

Feb 2019 - Present I Salesforce

Lead DevOps Engineer

Lead DevOps engineer, supporting Desk.com and the LiveMessaging platform. Currently focused on automating various aspects of infrastructure and operations, including disaster recovery.

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019 I Apptio

Senior DevOps Engineer

Senior DevOps Engineer on the Technical Operations team. Supported legacy, onpremise datacenter applications, as well as greenfield deployments in AWS using state-of-the-art tooling.

Jul 2016 - Nov 2017 I The Walt Disney Company

Senior Systems Engineer

Systems Engineer on the Enterprise Messaging and Foundational Services Team. Primary focus is designing and deploying DevOps infrastructure, as well as migration of critical application stacks to the cloud.

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016 I Amazon

Technical Operations Team Lead

Team Lead for Seattle-based Technical Operations Support Team.

Aug 2014 - Jul 2016 I Amazon

Technical Operations Support Engineer

Operations Engineer supporting AWS and Amazon.com, provided monitoring and maintenance of the largest e-commerce and cloud platform in the world.

Jun 2013 - Aug 2014 I Centurylink/Level(3)

CDN NOC Linux Admin

System administration focused on maintenance, monitoring, and triage for a global CDN with multiple thousands of Linux nodes.